Hello everyone and welcome to
another great lesson here at English Pod.
My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine
and today we've got an
upper intermediate
level lesson for you all.
That's right we're
going to talk a little
bit about business
and specifically we are in
a business meeting where we're
trying to sell something to someone.
That's right so you're
going to hear a lot of
talk about chocolate or in
this case gourmet bambons.
Bambons is another word for
chocolate candies or candies.
Okay so a bambon is kind
of like round usually right?
Usually.
Yes.
Okay.
All right so let's get
started and listen to
today's dialogue we'll
be back in a moment.
I'm glad you could find time
to meet with me Mr. Johnson.
I can't think of a nicer
environment for our meeting today.
The ambience here is lovely.
No problem.
If possible I always combine
business with pleasure.
Now let's hear more about
these chocolates you're offering.
Well as you know I
have recently become the
sole distributor for grangers gourmet
bambons here in the United States.
There are new manufacturer and are
looking to break into the luxury market.
Naturally your restaurant
sprang into my mind immediately.
I think your brand exemplifies many of the
same traits as grangers and serving these
chocolates would really
add to your reputation
for providing elegant
luxurious first class dining.
Mmm sounds interesting gourmet chocolates.
Where they produce Belgium?
Actually the factory is
located in Scotland really.
I didn't think they were known for
their luxury chocolate production.
That's what makes this
such a fantastic opportunity.
The government is 100% supportive of creating
new export markets and has guaranteed
a low tariff for all wholesale
orders of over 1,000 units.
They've also reduced the red
tape involved at customs as well.
Here I brought these especially for you.
Try one.
Ooh thanks.
Mmm.
Creamy texture?
Very smooth.
Unique aren't they?
I bet you've never tasted anything like it.
Quality is assured as
I personally visit the
factory to make sure
no one's cutting corners
with the ingredients only the creme
de la creme make it through inspection.
Yes.
Very interesting flavors.
Slightly spicy.
Mmm.
Very unique.
That's for sure.
Exactly what are the ingredients?
I have it on highest authority
that this traditional secret
recipe has been handed down in
the granger family for generations.
I'm sure you can keep a secret.
Water milk, cow beans, sugar, and hakis.
Hagis.
What's Hagis?
It's a traditional Scottish delicacy.
You take sheep's liver, heart, and lung
and stuff it inside the sheep's stomach.
I'll get back to you.
Mr. Johnson?
Alright we're back so a lot
of interesting vocab there.
The guy was trying to
convince him about these
chocolates but it turned
out to be something
a little bit strange and we'll
talk about that in a little while.
Before we get into
that why don't we take a
look at seven key words that we have
prepared for you today on language take away?
Language take away.
Okay so we've divided language
take away into two parts today.
The first part is all about
business and manufacturing.
So what's our first word Marco?
Alright so the guy talked
about being the sole
distributor for this company called
grangers gourmet bomb bombs.
Okay a distributor,
okay this is a person or
a company and the distributor is someone
who distributes or sells a product right?
Right so the factory
will make them, he will
get all these goods
from the factory and
then he will be the one that
gives it to the different retail stores.
So he can have many
clients and he is the
main person who you
get it from so obviously
they don't get it
directly from the factory.
Okay so this person a distributor or a
company is in the middle of the transaction.
And one side there is
the manufacturer and
on the other side there is
the retail market or stores.
Exactly and as you said that's our
second key word today manufacturer.
Okay manufacturer again is a
person or company that makes a good.
So for example a television
manufacturer makes TV, it's like a factory.
Exactly.
So they manufacture things, they make them.
Alright so we've got
distributors who are moving
goods, we have manufacturers
who are making them.
But what happens when we want
to move a good out of a country?
Okay so that is our third word for today.
Usually in customs we have to
pay a tariff for these goods or a tax.
Okay so a tariff is a special kind of tax
that you pay when you are trying to export
or send outside of your country
goods that you've made in that country.
So for example if I
make a hundred TVs in
America but I want to sell these TVs to
someone in Mexico I have to pay a tariff.
I have to pay like
ten dollars to the
government that allows me to
send these out of the country.
That's right.
So that is a tariff and now when he was
talking about tariffs and how the government
is reducing the tariffs
in order to motivate
business he talked
about also that the
government is reducing
or cutting the red tape.
Okay so he says listen they've also
reduced the red tape involved at customs.
So this means that before
they were encountering
some problems at
customs because customs
you know there is a lot
of paperwork, there is
a lot of taxes, there is a lot of
information you have to provide.
It is a hassle.
It is a lot of work.
A lot of paperwork.
Right so this kind of paperwork, bureaucracy,
this is called red tape in English.
For example I would
love to get a visa for
my foreign husband but
there is a lot of red tape.
There is a lot of work that we have to do.
There is a lot of bureaucratic
processes that you have to do.
All right so red tape
this means a lot of
paperwork, a lot of
work that you have to do.
Okay so those are key words
that are related to business.
Now let's move on to a
couple of different adjectives.
The first one when he talked
about chocolates he said elegant.
He said that something is elegant.
Okay elegant this is
a great adjective, you
are going to see this on
a lot of luxury brand items.
Elegant means something is elegant if it
is classy, if it looks really good and rich
or you could say that dress is very
elegant, that mink coat is very elegant.
Okay this is a positive thing.
So something that looks kind
of expensive at times as well.
Yeah that's right.
Another word that means looking
expensive or elegant is luxurious.
Okay so luxurious comes
from the noun luxury.
That's right luxury luxurious.
So we can say that the executive
suites at this hotel are very luxurious.
They have a jacuzzi, a king
size bed, expensive silk sheets.
The best quality materials.
So you can say that elegant and
luxurious kind of go hand in hand.
That's right.
Although elegance you
usually say about someone
or their clothing or even a car but luxurious
is more like object lace or an object.
Okay good.
And then we have
one final word that also
describes something that is very
rare or very good and rich, a delicacy.
Yeah actually this one
is a noun it's a thing
so we can say that this
is a Scottish delicacy
or what are the
delicacies in your country?
So delicacy is something that's special.
So for example you've
told me that an Ecuador
there are some
interesting food delicacies.
Little animals.
Yeah for example guinea pigs.
Well they're not really a
delicacy although kind of because
guinea pigs are expensive
compared to chickens for example.
So it is considered to be something
that you only eat on special occasions.
Right and in East Asia many people
consider sharks fin soup to be a delicacy.
Right.
Special dish.
Well we can say that
it's usually about food
and it's rare or something that's rare
or special or also can be very expensive.
That's right a delicacy.
Okay so a lot of great
interesting words on language
take away why don't we
move on now to fluency builder.
Fluency builder.
This first phrase is
actually something I try
to do is often as possible
but it's usually very difficult.
I combine business with pleasure.
Right.
Now this is a whole
phrase and this talks
about doing business
but at the same time
doing it in a fun way
or an interesting way.
Right so pleasure here means something
that is fun or entertainment even.
So for example going
out to dinner with your
company is a way to combine
business with pleasure.
All right or meeting a client at a bar
is combining business with pleasure.
So you're combining things that are
fun and things that are work related.
Right because you can
have a business meeting
in a boardroom or in a business or in a
meeting room but if you have the same
business meeting at a
bar where you're talking
and laughing but also
at the same time talking
business then you're
combining business with pleasure.
That's right.
And now for a second phrase
it's more about cheating right.
Somebody that is cheating
or maybe not doing
things correctly they
are cutting corners.
That's right so cutting corners
is another way to say cheating.
For example, I've seen people, students
cutting corners with their studies.
You think about cutting corners it
means that you're not going the long way.
Right.
You're cheating by going the shorter way.
You're taking a shortcut.
Taking a shortcut.
So for example instead
of studying for that
final test in math some people
write the formulas on their hands.
Right.
This is a way to cut corners.
You're actually cheating by putting
it on your hand making it easier.
So to cut corners is
to cheat or to try to
take the shortcut but it kind of
has a negative connotation right.
Oh definitely.
So most people will say don't cut corners.
In the end it's not worth it.
Right.
And for our final phrase we
have one that it's in French.
So this one is in French
but it's also a very common
English phrase that's why
we're going to teach it to you.
The creme de la creme.
Okay. So literally in translated from
French that means the creme of the creme.
Right.
But in English we would say
that it's the best of the best.
The best of the best.
Very top.
So that's what this phrase means.
The best of the best.
The very top the most excellent.
So you could say
Harvard University attracts
the creme de la creme of
American high school students.
Okay.
So the very best of American
high school students.
All right, so that phrase, it's in French
but you can say it in English, right?
Like like Fiancé, for example.
Fiancé, creme de la creme.
These are all words that we've stolen
from French and we use in English.
So no, don't worry about how
you pronounce it in English.
We just say creme de la creme.
Okay.
So why don't we listen
to this dialogue for
the last time and we'll
be back in just a bit.
I'm glad you could find time
to meet with me, Mr. Johnson.
I can't think of a nicer
environment for our meeting today.
The ambience here is lovely.
No problem.
If possible, I always combine
business with pleasure.
Now let's hear more about
these chocolates you're offering.
Well, as you know, I have
recently become the sole distributor
for Granger's gourmet bond
bonds here in the United States.
They're a new manufacturer and are
looking to break into the luxury market.
Naturally, your restaurant
sprang into my mind immediately.
I think your brand exemplifies many of the
same traits as Granger's and serving these
chocolates would really
add to your reputation
for providing elegant,
luxurious, first-class
dining.
Hmm.
Sounds interesting.
Gourmet chocolates.
Where are they produced, Belgium?
Actually, the factory is
located in Scotland, really.
I didn't think they were known for
their luxury chocolate production.
That's what makes this
such a fantastic opportunity.
The government is 100%
supportive of creating
new export markets
and has guaranteed a low
tariff for all wholesale
orders of over 1,000 units.
They've also reduced the red
tape involved at customs as well.
Here, I brought these especially for you.
Try one.
Oh, thanks.
Hmm.
Creamy texture?
Very smooth.
Unique, aren't they?
I bet you've never tasted anything like it.
Creamy is assured
as I personally visit the
factory to make sure
no one's cutting corners
with the ingredients, only the creme
de la creme make it through inspection.
Yes.
Very interesting flavors, slightly spicy.
Hmm.
Very unique.
That's for sure.
Exactly what are the ingredients?
I have it on highest authority
that this traditional secret
recipe has been handed down in
the Granger family for generations.
I'm sure you can keep a secret.
Better milk, cacao
beans, sugar, and haggis.
Haggis.
What's haggis?
It's a traditional Scottish delicacy.
You take sheep's liver, heart, and lung,
and stuff it inside the sheep's stomach.
I'll get back to you.
Mr. Johnson?
Mr. Johnson.
All right, we're back so
now this Scottish delicacy.
What is this haggis?
Haggis.
I've never actually eaten it.
It does sound pretty disgusting.
It's a Scottish delicacy that I
think involves stuffing, like what?
What do we hear?
Pig liver?
Let's see this again.
Luckily, you take a
sheep's liver, a heart,
and a lung, and you
put it inside the sheep's
stomach, and you serve that,
so it's kind of-- And you cook it.
Yeah, you cook it like that.
You cook it, and so it's like
all the insides of a sheep.
Yeah.
It kind of sounds
disgusting, but I'm pretty
sure it tastes pretty good,
because it's a Scottish delicacy.
It's a Scottish delicacy, though.
Yeah, I don't know, although I
cannot imagine eating it in a chocolate.
This is disgusting.
I've heard of countries
where they take
chicken, they stuff it
with something, like they
have a stuffing, and
then they put the chicken
inside a goat, and
then the goat inside
a bigger animal, and then
they cook all that together.
Oh, wow.
And then you have this
amazing-- obviously, it's huge.
They use these big
brick ovens to cook them,
but you have this platter with
three different types of meats.
Oh, wow.
We have that in America.
Really?
It's called a turducken.
Turkey?
Duck and chicken.
So you have a chicken inside of a
duck, which you put inside of a turkey.
Turkey, wow.
And you bake it.
Wow.
How does it taste?
Delicious.
It's very special taste, yeah.
Exactly.
So I'm curious to know
what your national delicacy is.
Do you have a delicacy
in your home country?
Let us know on EnglishPod.com.
We're always curious
to talk about food, but
we would love to have
you practicing on the
website and asking any
questions that you may have.
That's right.
So we'll see everyone there.
See you next time.
Bye.